<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- 
// 
// This is the place for your statements. The maximum 
// number of statements is theoretically unlimited, but
// less then 50 statements are advisable.
// If your are using German Umlauts and other special 
// characters, make sure, that you save this XML-file 
// as an UTF-8-document. White-space inbetween the 
// nodes are ignored. Any white-space within the text-
// nodes, including leading or trailing whitespace and 
// line breaks, is preserved.
//
// EXAMPLE
// Let's define some statements concerning FlashQ:
// Statement 1: FlashQ is very usefull.
// Statement 2: I prefer offline surveys.
// Statement 3: FlashQ is too complicated to configure.
//
// Each statement requires a seperate statement-node 
// consisting out of an opening and a closing tag. The 
// statement itself goes between this two tags. 
// The unique statement id is saved as an 
// attribute called 'id'. We have three exmaple 
// statements and we need therefore three statement-
// nodes and one parent-node. 
//
// <statements version="1.0" htmlparse="false">
//   <statement id="1">FlashQ is very usefull.</statement>
//   <statement id="2">I prefer offline surveys.</statement>
//   <statement id="3">FlashQ is too complicated to configure</statement>
// </statements>
// 
// ===================================================
// 
-->

<statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
  <statement id = "1">There is a natural greenhouse effect that gives us liveable conditions on earth. (1)</statement>
  <statement id = "2">There is an enhanced greenhouse effect causes by anthropogenic emissions. (2)</statement>
  <statement id = "3">Climate does not equal carbon. (3)</statement>
  <statement id = "4">Carbon is transferred between different reservoirs on earth (in the carbon cycle). (4)</statement>
  <statement id = "5">There are multiple sources and sinks for different greenhouse gases. (5)</statement>
  <statement id = "6">There are lots of data sources that evidence climate change. (6)</statement>
  <statement id = "7">Climate change is the shifting of environmental conditions due to both natural processes and human activities. (7)</statement>
  <statement id = "8">Global average temperatures have always varied but changes since the industrial revolution have been far faster. (8)</statement>
  <statement id = "9">Climate is different to weather. (9)</statement>
  <statement id = "10">Climate change is caused by an imbalance between the amount of energy entering and leaving the earth. (10)</statement>
  <statement id = "11">Energy is transferred between different stores; human activities can alter both the total amount and distribution of energy in the earth system. (11)</statement>
  <statement id = "12">Human-induced emissions of greenhouse gases are changing the frequency and intensity of extreme weather events. (12)</statement>
  <statement id = "13">There are multiple greenhouse gases (not just carbon dioxide). (13)</statement>
  <statement id = "14">Different greenhouse gases have different lifetimes. (14)</statement>
  <statement id = "15">Different greenhouse gases have different warming potentials. (15)</statement>
  <statement id = "16">Ocean acidification is one aspect of global climate change. (16)</statement>
  <statement id = "17">Climate change is already happening, and is having an impact in the UK. (17)</statement>
  <statement id = "18">Holes in the ozone layer and global warming are separate problems. (18)</statement>
  <statement id = "19">Feedback loops can reinforce the initial changes. (19)</statement>
  <statement id = "20">There are planetary boundaries and limits. (20)</statement>
  <statement id = "21">There is a long history and disciplinarity of climate science. (21)</statement>
  <statement id = "22">Measuring global temperatures is complex and involves a range of techniques. (22)</statement>
  <statement id = "23">Combustion of fossil fuels as part of industrial processes, transportation and energy production, drives climate change. (23)</statement>
  <statement id = "24">Agricultural practices can drive climate change. (24)</statement>
  <statement id = "25">The impacts of climate change are unevenly distributed. (25)</statement>
  <statement id = "26">Climate change poses a number of risks that will impact England. (26)</statement>
  <statement id = "27">Climate change is not concerned with international borders. (27)</statement>
  <statement id = "28">The climate crisis is one of several anthropogenic drivers of a biodiversity crisis. (28)</statement>
  <statement id = "29">Climate change has many secondary risks. (29)</statement>
  <statement id = "30">There is inequality in peoples’ capacity to respond to the risks and impacts of climate change. (30)</statement>
  <statement id = "31">Representative Concentration Pathways (RCPs) are used by climate scientists to predict and describe the effects of climate change in different emissions scenarios. (31)</statement>
  <statement id = "32">SSPs (Shared Socioeconomic Pathways) SSPs are used to link the different RCPs to a description of the kind of societies that would lead to them happening. (32)</statement>
  <statement id = "33">There is a difference between uncertainty and a complete lack of knowledge. (33)</statement>
  <statement id = "34">Estimates of uncertainty vary. (34)</statement>
  <statement id = "35">Adaptation is different to mitigation. (35)</statement>
  <statement id = "36">There is international variation in per-capita CO2 emissions. (36)</statement>
  <statement id = "37">Massive societal transformation is required for a Just Transition. (37)</statement>
  <statement id = "38">There are lots of solutions to the climate crisis, these solutions have benefits and drawbacks. (38)</statement>
  <statement id = "39">We need climate-driven innovation. (39)</statement>
  <statement id = "40">Policy plays a role in climate change mitigation. (40)</statement>
  <statement id = "41">International climate negotiations involve multiple steps to reach agreement. (41)</statement>
  <statement id = "42">The legal nature of agreements from international climate negotiations impacts implementation.(42)</statement>
  <statement id = "43">There is a conflict between current education policy and climate education. (43)</statement>
  <statement id = "44">Mitigating and adapting to climate change involves moral and political choices. (44)</statement>
  <statement id = "45">Countries have Common But Differentiated Responsibility (CBDR). (45)</statement>
  <statement id = "46">Equitable Burden-sharing demands the fair distribution of responsibilities. (46)</statement>
  <statement id = "47">Intergenerational justice: decisions made today about climate change affect future generations. (47)</statement>
  <statement id = "48">Climate doomism-climate outcomes are a continuum- not binary. (48)</statement>
  <statement id = "49">Cognitive biases can influence the way we interpret and process information. (49)</statement>
  <statement id = "50">Interdependence: Humans are an integral part of nature, not separate from it. (50)</statement>
  <statement id = "51">Active hope requires taking meaningful action. (51)</statement>
  <statement id = "52">Carbon footprint is just one way to think about responsibility for emissions. (52)</statement>
  <statement id = "53">Media sources have biases and frame information differently. (53)</statement>
  <statement id = "54">There are psychological explanations for climate scepticism (why people try to cast doubt). (54)</statement>
  <statement id = "55">It is a false dichotomy to talk of individual or system change. (55)</statement>
  <statement id = "56">Individual action can inspire others. (56)</statement>
  <statement id = "57">Proactive Civic Engagement and voting is needed for policy change. (57)</statement>
  <statement id = "58">Historically, protest had led to social transformation. (58)</statement>
  <statement id = "59">Action on the climate crisis is urgent. (59)</statement>
  <statement id = "60">The science of climate change is (very) complicated! (60)</statement>
  <statement id = "61">Climate change is a risk amplifier. (61)</statement>
  <statement id = "62">In non-linear systems there is unpredictability and chaos. (62)</statement>
  <statement id = "63">Climate change operates on different time scales. (63)</statement>
</statements>