<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- 
// 
// This is the place for your statements. The maximum 
// number of statements is theoretically unlimited, but
// less then 50 statements are advisable.
// If your are using German Umlauts and other special 
// characters, make sure, that you save this XML-file 
// as an UTF-8-document. White-space inbetween the 
// nodes are ignored. Any white-space within the text-
// nodes, including leading or trailing whitespace and 
// line breaks, is preserved.
//
// EXAMPLE
// Let's define some statements concerning FlashQ:
// Statement 1: FlashQ is very usefull.
// Statement 2: I prefer offline surveys.
// Statement 3: FlashQ is too complicated to configure.
//
// Each statement requires a seperate statement-node 
// consisting out of an opening and a closing tag. The 
// statement itself goes between this two tags. 
// The unique statement id is saved as an 
// attribute called 'id'. We have three exmaple 
// statements and we need therefore three statement-
// nodes and one parent-node. 
//
// <statements version="1.0" htmlparse="false">
//   <statement id="1">FlashQ is very usefull.</statement>
//   <statement id="2">I prefer offline surveys.</statement>
//   <statement id="3">FlashQ is too complicated to configure</statement>
// </statements>
// 
// ===================================================
// 
-->

<statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
  <statement id = "1">The natural greenhouse effect sustains Earth's habitable conditions.</statement>
  <statement id = "2">There is an additional greenhouse effect caused by anthropogenic emissions.</statement>
  <statement id = "3">Climate change is not just about carbon dioxide.</statement>
  <statement id = "4">Carbon dioxide (carbon) is distributed between various sinks and stores, including the oceans.</statement>
  <statement id = "5">There are lots of data sources that evidence how climate has changed over thousands of years. </statement>
  <statement id = "6">Climate and weather are distinct. Climate change is the shifting of environmental conditions due to both natural processes and human activities.</statement>
  <statement id = "7">Global average temperatures have always varied, but changes since the industrial revolution have been far faster.</statement>
  <statement id = "8">Climate change results from an imbalance between the amount of energy entering and leaving the earth (sometimes called a forcing), which can either be natural (e.g. orbital variations) or anthropogenic.</statement>
  <statement id = "9">Human-induced emissions of greenhouse gases are changing the frequency and intensity of extreme weather events.</statement>
  <statement id = "10">Different greenhouses gases have different lifetimes.</statement>
  <statement id = "11">Different greenhouse gases have different warming potentials.</statement>
  <statement id = "12">Climate change has many secondary risks and impacts such as biodiversity loss and ocean acidification.</statement>
  <statement id = "13">Climate impacts are happening now, but the impacts are unevenly distributed.</statement>
  <statement id = "14">Feedback loops can amplify the impacts of climate change.</statement>
  <statement id = "15">There are planetary boundaries and limits.</statement>
  <statement id = "16">There is a long history and disciplinarity of climate science.</statement>
  <statement id = "17">Measuring global temperatures is complex and involves a range of techniques.</statement>
  <statement id = "18">Agricultural practices are a significant driver of climate change.</statement>
  <statement id = "19">Climate change is not concerned with international borders.</statement>
  <statement id = "20">Countries have Common but Differentiated Responsibility (CBDR).</statement>
  <statement id = "21">Representative Concentration Pathways (RCPs) are used by climate scientists to predict and describe the effects of climate change in different emissions scenarios.</statement>
  <statement id = "22">Shared Socioeconomic Pathways (SSPs) are used to link the different RCPs to a description of the kind of societies that would lead to them happening.</statement>
  <statement id = "23">There is a difference between uncertainty and a complete lack of knowledge.</statement>
  <statement id = "24">Adaptation is different to mitigation.</statement>
  <statement id = "25">There is international variation in per-capita CO2 emissions; countries with higher per capita emissions will require greater changes to reach net zero.</statement>
  <statement id = "26">Massive societal transformation is required for a Just Transition.</statement>
  <statement id = "27">The legal nature of international climate agreements can impact the level of commitment and accountability associated with them.</statement>
  <statement id = "28">The importance of topics learned in school is not always aligned with their weight in formal exams.</statement>
  <statement id = "29">Ethical dilemmas arise in climate change adaptation and mitigation because these efforts often involve complex trade-offs, competing values, and distributional impacts.</statement>
  <statement id = "30">Equitable Burden-sharing demands the fair distribution of responsibilities.</statement>
  <statement id = "31">Decisions made today about climate change affect future generations.</statement>
  <statement id = "32">Climate outcomes are a continuum, not binary. Each step we take to mitigate climate change will avert a worse-case scenario.</statement>
  <statement id = "33">Cognitive biases can influence the way we interpret and process information. </statement>
  <statement id = "34">Humans are an integral part of nature, not separate from it.</statement>
  <statement id = "35">Active hope requires taking meaningful action.</statement>
  <statement id = "36">Carbon footprint is a tool designed to assign responsibility for emissions to specific individuals, organisations, and actions at the point of use.</statement>
  <statement id = "37">Media sources have biases and frame information differently.</statement>
  <statement id = "38">It is a false dichotomy to talk of individual or system change; we need both.</statement>
  <statement id = "39">Proactive civic engagement and voting is needed for policy change.</statement>
  <statement id = "40">Historically, protest had led to social transformation. </statement>
  <statement id = "41">Action on the climate crisis is urgent.</statement>
  <statement id = "42">The science of climate change is (very) complicated.</statement>
  <statement id = "43">Climate change is a risk amplifier.</statement>
  <statement id = "44">Several different futures are possible.</statement>
  <statement id = "45">In non-linear systems there is unpredictability and chaos.</statement>
  <statement id = "46">Climate change operates on different time scales.</statement>
</statements>